FREDERICK LOPEZ

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | UI/UX DEVELOPER

CONTACT

431-877-5932

frederickpiadolopez@gmail.com

www.fredericklopez.com

in <u>linkedin.com/in/frederick-lopez-</u> 5a1a125b

https://github.com/freddy-lopezdev

PROFILE

Pixel enthusiast with 6 years experience as a UX designer and software developer. A self-starter working independently or leading a team to a collaborative solution can lead to cutting-edge technology research and knowledge.

Assuring users' **empathy** when developing and designing applications.

SKILLS

Technical

REACT

NEXTJS

JavaScript

HTML

CSS

C#

MVC

SQL

Selenium

Postman

GitHub

UX Research

Prototyping

Wireframing

WORK EXPERIENCE

UI/UX Developer

GAC - Dubai, UAE 2015 - 2021

- Managed a small team of UX designers to organize their day-today tasks of doing research and design. Each of the members has a good output on every sprint release.
- Designed one of the biggest applications in GAC with the help of product owners and stakeholders. The design was submitted and launched to the public with returning clients as a bonus.
- Worked with a graphic designer to implement the design specification that will be forwarded to the developers. It boosts their productivity and the outcome of the applications.
- Converted one of the legacy apps into the latest technology (Silverlight to HTML5)
 - Conducted UX research with the proprietor users to create personas, journey mapping, and empathy mapping.
 - Worked with the user by sketching the pages on paper to determine the actual application functionality.
 - Prototyped the initial high fidelity design to have a better outcome and also to define what the sprint epic on a user wants vs needs mapping.

FREDERICK LOPEZ

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | UI/UX DEVELOPER

SKILLS

Professional

Analytical
Problem Solving

Emphathetic

Goal Oriented

Tech Savvy

EDUCATION

Software Development

Manitoba Institute of

Trades and Technology

Manitoba - Canada

Jan 2022 - Dec 2022

BS Computer Science

Adamson University

Manila - Philippines

June 2008 - March 2013

CERTIFICATION

Scrum Foundation

Scrum Alliance - 2022

WORK EXPERIENCE

System Analyst

Mobiiworld - Dubai, UAE 2014 - 2015

- Maintains a good quality application by doing functional testing and exploratory testing. Fewer bugs and issues are reported by the client on every sprint.
- Developed automated testing for the mobile applications for every released version. It maintains the application's stable version and easy for the tester to do regression.
- Handled user acceptance testing for every client that determines the ratio of each application's success.
- Maintains a wide range of test documents for every application that's been used as standards for company quality releases.

NOTABLE PROJECTS

Lumen8 - Dubai UAE

Next JS Ecommerce solution

Live Demo

Land Rover OYL - Dubai UAE

Map Tracking Device

♠ Live Demo

Supreme ICS - Canada

Food Ordering App

Live Demo

GAC Port Now - Dubai UAE

Customer Portal Solution

Live Demo

REFERENCES

Lena De Geer

Regional IT Manager - Dubai Upon request

Chris MacDonald

Instructor Upon request